MD TAMZID HASAN

Home Address

House- 268, Flat- C4, Jafrabad, West Dhanmondi, Dhaka-1207, Bangladesh +880 1711 927924

Work Address

NSU Global Health Institute Plot- 15, Block- B, Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka- 1229, Bangladesh

Email: tamzid.hasan@northsouth.edu

Career Objective

To build up a career in public health and development, including research. Experienced in developing and preparing tools, data collection, data sorting, updating the database, and preparing project budgets based on research demand. Multitasking, solid team-building capacity, strong leadership, and interpersonal communication skills.

Education

North South University Master of Public Health Grade Point Average: 3.88 on a 4.00 scale.

December 2022

Work Experience

Jhpiego Bangladesh, Gulshan-2, Dhaka

January 2023 – February 2023

- Develop a Health Facility Readiness Assessment Tool for Maternal Immunization in Bangladesh.
- Collaboration with EPI & Surveillance, MNCAH, Directorate General of Health Services, Ministry of Health and Family Welfare, Bangladesh.
- Propose and prepare a draft new tool for assessing facility readiness for the provision of maternal immunization

NSU Global Health Institute (NGHI), Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka

August 2022 – December 2023

- Proposal and questionnaire development, field survey, data monitoring, and data entry.
- Grant proposal writing for the fund and development of the project.
- Manuscript writing for publication

Department of Public Health, North South University, Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka June 2022 – January 2023

- Assist faculty members with classroom instruction, exams, record keeping, and other miscellaneous projects and develop course plans.
- Assist academic staff with the development or update of learning materials, proctor exams, and record grades in the grade book.
- Course curriculum development for the undergraduate students.
- Tutor or mentor students in class or outside.

S. S. Engineering & Construction, Bangla Motor, Dhaka

October 2013 – July 2017

- Survey the site & manage the design and construction of electrical systems.
- Prepare specifications for the purchase of materials and equipment.

Mr. Tamzid's Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

• Develop budgets, estimating labor, materials, and construction costs.

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd., Banani, Dhaka

November 2011 – July 2012

- Installation, commissioning, maintenance, & design of the solar system.
- To assist in designing, installing, commissioning, and maintaining solar photovoltaic (PV) systems.
- Prepare reports and design specifications, conduct research, and training, and supervise technicians.

Honors and Scholarship

- Adlerbert Foreign Student Hospitality Foundation- 2019 & 2020, International student scholarship for master's program.
- University Scholarship- Master of Public Health at North South University.
- Erasmus+ scholarship- Attend the training on Project Management in Athens, Greece.
- Scholarship from Council of Europe- attend the study session of Peace in the Spotlight in Strasbourg, France.

Mr. Tamzid's Portfolio: www.tamzid.info